LEIF HUHN

Chicago, IL 60660 leif.n.huhn@gmail.com (415) 583-5685

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Site-reliability / Tools & Automation engineer with over 20 years of experience in a wide variety of technologies and platforms. Strengths in managing apps running in large Kubernetes clusters in AWS EC2 and other clouds. Knowledge of Docker best practices and experience with Python, Go, and build systems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wish 2019 – 2020

Software Engineer

REMOTE San Francisco, CA

- · Refactored Docker containers running Wish's development and production primary web app and other infrastructure.
- · Upgraded the containers running wish.com from Ubuntu 14.04 to 18.04.
- · Troubleshot multi-threaded applications running on Kubernetes.
- · Packaged and contributed to open source developer tools in Go
- · Maintained Docker builds in Gitlab and Go build pipelines in Launchpad.
- · Tutored junior coworkers in best practices.
- · Participated in on-call rotation for both Tools & Automation, as well as the site-up on-call for wish.com.

CenturyLink Cloud

2015 - 2019

Senior Lead Software Developer

REMOTE Bellevue, WA / St. Louis, MO

- · Managed cloud services in both AWS and CenturyLink cloud.
- · Used SaltStack to manage Linux, Hadoop, HBase, Zookeeper, Kafka, and Elastic Search.
- · Deployed Consul in multi-datacenter mesh in order to support application failover.
- · Used Bash and Go scripting for various system administration purposes.
- · Created a virtual firewall product for CenturyLink's cloud using NSX Edge firewalling.
- · Migrated features from a monolithic control portal to microservices running on Kubernetes.

Riverbed Technology

2010 - 2015

Team Lead

San Francisco, CA

- · Mentored junior coders.
- · Conceived of, collaboratively designed, and oversaw development of an automated program "Rack-and-Roll," greatly simplifying the process of adding new hardware into the lab.
- · Created system to power down unused testing machines, saving power, cooling, and money.
- · Automated VMWare vCenter to automate the installation and testing of VMs.
- · Troubleshot various DHCP, TFTP, and PXE networking problems.
- · Troubleshot problems with internal appliance manufacturing, including bugs in the unreleased product, bugs in the build system, hardware problems, user error, networking problems, service outages, etc.
- · Made OO design decisions for future direction of testing codebase.

 $System\ Administrator$

2003 - 2010Berkeley, CA

- · Installed, maintained, and updated Linux and Windows servers providing critical infrastructure (mail, web, dns, nfs, mysql, iptables, RAID, LVM, and ssh).
- · Managed remote servers for multiple law firms. Worked with system administrators from client companies to resolve networking problems.
- · Transitioned our systems to 64-bit to allow processing of larger datasets.
- · Evaluated server workloads and made purchasing decisions.
- · Used Nagios to provide 24/7/365 monitoring of critical services.
- · Automated backup processes.

Drogin, Kakigi & Associates

Web Developer

2001 - 2003Berkeley, CA

- · Developed Model-View-Controller web framework with a MySQL backend tailored for the specific needs of the company.
- · Created websites to allow hundreds of paralegals from around the country to work together to interview thousands of plaintiffs in large class action lawsuits.
- · Oversaw and trained junior web developers.

Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission

Web Developer

1999 - 2000Tallahassee, FL

· Developed data heavy client side web applications and managed IIS.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

· Python, C/C++, Java, Go.

· VMWare ESX, VMWare NSX, vCenter, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, KVM

- · SQL, NoSQL databases, Hadoop, HBase
- · Zookeeper, Kafka, Consul, Couchbase
- · RabbitMQ, Redis
- \cdot MySQL
- · Puppet, Salt, Linux, Git, cgroups
- · DNS
- · Icinga, Nagios, Kibana, Graphite, Grafana,

Prometheus

- · RAID, LVM, NFS
- · tcpdump, wireshark
- · Unix Scripting: POSIX sh, bash, expect
- · Windows Deployment, Hyper-V, cygwin
- · macOS, homebrew
- · AWS EC2, ECR, S3, CloudTrail
- · LATEX

EDUCATION & HOBBIES

- · University of California, Berkeley, CA Bachelors Degree in Physics
- · Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL
 - Completed University Honors Program. GPA: 3.9
- · Some experience patching Linux kernel and gemu.
- · Conversational in American Sign Language, some knowledge of Spanish, French, and Japanese